<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>Beigesoftware, Beige-WEB-Store</title>
   </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="Beige WEB Store specification. Filtering list of goods/services.">

    <h4>List filtering</h4>
    <p>Buyer can search needed merchandise by selecting desired specifics e.g. "weight, manufacturing year/date, type operation system...".
      It also can filter list with "non-specifics" attributes like price, availability in chosen place...
      Filter is always applied to the merchandise of same type, e.g. notebooks, computers (set), CPU block, cars, trucks, motorcycles...
      List (catalog) "on start" can consist of merchandises of different types. Catalog/sub-catalog is set of already filtered items.
      Only big catalogs (of similar items) needs/allows to be filtered. Web-shop can use only catalog and use filter to filter items.
      E.g. catalog "cars", any car has choosable specific "manufacture" that can be used in filter.
      So web-store admin should itself choose catalog that can be filtered and set of specifics for filter.
      If buyer select such catalog or its subcatalog then filter will be enabled for using.
    </p>
    <h5>Availability in pickup place filtering.</h5>
    <p>Pickup place is tied with availability. This is no reason to add it as goods/service specifics.
      For hotel booking this filter is often used. To use this filter set "usePickupPlaceFilter" in a catalog.
      There are two kinds of this filter:
      <ul>
        <li>list of selected pickup places</li>
        <li>distance from a point, e.g. 20km around latitude/longitude 41.12312/45.1231232</li>
      </ul>
      Model EPickupPlaceFilterType:
      <ul>
        <li>LIST</li>
        <li>DISTANCE</li>
      </ul>
    </p>
    <h5>Filter "available since/at/from-till".</h5>
    <p>
      This is the main filter for booking hotel and many other service. In that case (booking hotel)
      when buyer selected catalog then it will be empty list and opened filter for date selecting.
      Model EDateFilterType:
      <ul>
        <li>SINCE_DAY</li>
        <li>AT_DAY</li>
        <li>AT_TIME - day, hour, minutes</li>
        <li>FROM_TILL_DAY</li>
        <li>FROM_TILL_TIME - day, hour, minutes (e.g. for hourly rent of something).</li>
      </ul>
    </p>
    <h5>Filter price</h5>
    <p>If catalog has any filter then filter "price" will be added automatically. No one uses only filter "price".</p>

    </section>

  </body>

</document>
