<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>Beigesoft™ WEB Store specification #1. Shopping cart.</title>
   </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="Beigesoft™ WEB Store specification #1. Shopping cart.">
      
      <h4>Common information, requirements.</h4>
      <p>A buyer can order goods and services that belong to web-store owner and other sellers.
        Depends of seller tax methods maybe different. During cart check out, it's created customer order for each seller.
        In all countries law is similar about payment - 100% by default, otherwise it should be agreement (contract) signed by seller and buyer.
        In case of partially paid, it's might be created separated orders for the same seller,
        e.g. one that 100% paid right now through any online payment system and another for payment after buyer received goods.
        This is maybe used for selling scheme - "buy 4, pay for 2 right now, pay the rest in 1 week or return 2 goods",
        or just "I'm not sure right now about seller or its goods".
        It's also maybe "a seller sells goods to a reseller and to want 30% prepayment".
        In these cases buyer can itself makes different carts/orders, e.g. first 30% on-line paid, second 70% will paid after.
      </p>
      <p>"Price inclusive of tax" is the most world-wide used method. For goods like "used car" buyer usually estimates and pays taxes by itself.
        Any way for ordinal taxable goods it's used tax methods in same way as in Beigesoft-Accounting.
        Buyer maybe foreigner and delivering by mail, so no taxes.
        Buyer maybe in other "Tax destination" region of the country, so it should be assigned by ZIP
        "DebtorCreditor.taxDestination" for owner's goods or "OnlineBuyer.taxDest" for S.E.goods.
        Buyer maybe reseller, and taxes maybe omitted (according the law).
        Because of cart can has multiply item's owners, taxes are separated and their methods maybe different,
        e.g. one "tax dest#1, half up, item basis" another "tax dest#2, half down, invoice basis".
        For "invoice basis" and cart dividing in two orders for same item's owner,
        total tax from cart maybe little bit different than in orders.
      </p>
      <p>Customer order does neither accounting nor warehouse entries, but it reduces "Goods Available in Place".
        Canceled order increases back "Goods Available in Place".
        Order with web-store owner's items is used to create Sales Invoice.
        S.E.Seller has no accounting/warehouse subsystem, but S.E.seller can print/send by email invoice from order's information.
        Order can be in one of statuses - "new/pending/closed/canceled".
        Orders is remained in database, buyers cart history - no, only the last (current).
        Buyers can see all their orders.
        After order has been done (status closed), invoice in default language (and in preferred one) will be sent to buyer by email automatically.
      </p>
      <p>Buyer (overseas) may prefer foreign currency. All prices are made in national currency.
        If web-store owner wants to offer goods in foreign currency, then it should add available foreign currency rates<b>CurrRate</b>
        and keep them up to date. Buyer can opt currency from offered list, cookie <b>wscurr</b> holds preferred/default currency ID,
        request variable with the same name holds the currency,
        price in foreign currency is calculated dynamically <b>price FC = price NC * currency rate</b>.
        All S.E. sellers should accept payments in any currency that is from web-store foreign currency list.
        Native buyers (or buyers that have the country's geolocation) may/should be restricted from choosing foreign currency.
        Cash payment is often made in native currency (e.g. foreign tourist pay during check-in),
        but it still can use other currency and pay with native one by using booking rate.
      </p>
      <p>Small store can offers goods only for locals, so no need to reveal destination tax category.
        And so does for goods that are offered only locally, e.g. "Hot food". That is if item has empty tax destination list, then it's used origin tax category (if taxable).
      </p>
      <p>Buyer's location maybe revealed by using HTML5-geolocation or buyer itself enters shipping address.
        If buyer prefer/should pickup good/service by himself (payment usually cash), then buyer's address maybe omitted.</p>
      <p>Shipping/handling price. Ordinal short-distance usually cost nothing to buyer.
        "In country" and overseas shipping and handling should be included into cart as "service" and it's usually taxable for "in country".
        These services should be included into cart automatically. They price usually depends of cart items.
        Because of it delivering method should be asked on first adding into cart. If buyer have changed delivering, then shipping service should be redone.
        Many shops has only delivering method, e.g. "free hot pizza delivering" or "buyer pickup itself for ordinal shop with Internet catalog", so "TradingSettings.onlyDeliv" should be set.
      </p>
      <p>Items measuring may have different decimal places e.g.:
        <ul>
          <li>Cable 3ft - 1</li>
          <li>Wire GH - 23.3ft</li>
        </ul>
        AItemPrice holds unit of measure to be printed in the catalog and step of unit (default 1).
        E.g.:
        <ul>
          <li>Wire GH 12USD, UOM ft, step 1 -> 1, 2, 3, etc.</li>
          <li>Wire GHA 12USD, UOM ft, step 0.5 -> 0.5, 1, 1.5, etc.</li>
          <li>Wire GHJ 32USD, UOM 4ft, step 1, -> 4, 8, 12, etc.</li>
        </ul>
        Printing default UOM "each" in catalog is excessive, so it should be leave empty in ItemPrice for such items.
        In the cart, order, invoice it will be assigned phantom variable <b>default UOM "each" ID=1</b> that presents "each",
        i.e. it's used reserved ID <b>1</b> that must be same for any beigesoft-accounting-oio database.
        Database holds quantity with 4 decimal  places (configured with Beige-ORM XML files).
        Accounting settings "quantity precision" holds number of decimal placed (less or equals 4) to which decimal number will be rounded and trailing zeros will be printed in invoice.
        There is no need to print trailing zeros in web-store's catalog or cart, so quantity <b>1.0</b> will be printed as <b>1</b>.
        If there is need to use and print in invoice (or catalog) different quantity precision for different goods, then item should has property <b>decimal places</b>.
        "Item price " property "unit step" can be used to reveal decimal places, e.g. "step 1.0 -> 0 DP", "step 0.25 -> 2 DP" and print trailing zeros in catalog and cart.
        HTML widget "input quantity" uses "unit step" to increasing, decreasing and rounding "item's quantity".
      </p>
      <p>Pickup place. In case when buyer orders items that are in different places and buyer want to pickup
        them by itself, then it should be different orders (and final paid invoices) for each place.
        Items in list usually has availability in all pickup places, during checkout item line maybe divided.
      </p>
      
      <h4>Revealing tax method</h4>
      <p>If "TradingSettings.overseas" is "Yes", then foreign buyer can select delivering method - "shipping overseas",
       so it's foreigner and taxes will be omitted.
       In case of "TradingSettings.txDests" is "Yes", when buyer has selected "shipping", then it must enter "ZIP" to find "tax destination".
       For numeric ZIP revealing tax destination is simple: any tax destination must has "regZip" filled with "comma separated ZIP range",
       e.g. "23450,14450" means any ZIP from 23450 to 14450. Otherwise assigning tax destination should be customized or made "by hand" (e.g. B2B with small number of customers).
      </p>
      <p>Buyer can change delivering method and zip, tax method and cart will be redone.</p>
      <p>If cart has item with tax destinations, and "in country shipping" and buyer's tax destination can not be made automatically, then buyer's cart will have "ask for tax method" button that enables "Cart.err" to highlight "this cart's buyer is waiting".</p>
      <p>If both "TradingSettings.overseas and txDests" is false, then it's used item's tax method independent of delivering,
        i.e. no need buyer's ZIP and delivering method.</p>

      <h4>Persistable models</h4>
      <p>OnlineBuyer:
        <ul>
          <li>AHasNameIdLongVersion (autogenerated ID) fields</li>
          <li>registeredPassword - String, null for unregistered buyer or for preferred authorization through a social network</li>
          <li>regCustomer - DebtorCreditor, it will be assigned/created when CustomerInvoice is created for request. No need for S.E.Seller.</li>
          <li><b>only for S.E. goods/services without creating "DebtorCreditor":</b></li>
          <li>regEmail - String, null for unregistered buyer</li>
          <li>regAddress1 - String, if applied</li>
          <li>regAddress2 - String, if applied</li>
          <li>regZip - String, if applied</li>
          <li>regCountry - String, if applied</li>
          <li>regState - String, if applied</li>
          <li>regCity - String, if applied</li>
          <li>regPhone - String, if applied</li>
          <li>tin - String, optional,  tax identification number.</li>
          <li>foreig - Boolean, is foreigner for omitting ST</li>
          <li>taxDest - TaxDestination, optional</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>TradingSettings.isCreateOnlineUserOnFirstVisit - create online user on first visit if there is no cookie "cUserId"
        and of course user unauthorized. False by default, otherwise it used for BI and tracking unauthorized users who even did not
        added any item to cart for farther suggesting goods.
      </p>
      <p>Any user has dedicated at first visit cookie <b>cBuyerId=OnlineBuyer.itsId</b>, so OnlineBuyer is created either immediately
        if TradingSettings.rememberUnauthorizedUserFor &gt; 0 or when cart check out.
        Unauthorized user (did not buy anything) can be deleted according TradingSettings.rememberUnauthorizedUserFor days.</p>
      <p>After user fist authorized it's created automatically their customer (DebtorCreditor) with DebtorCreditorCategory.
        It can be changed or assigned by hand. 
      </p>

      <p>CurrRate:
        <ul>
          <li>curr - Currency, PK</li>
          <li>rate - BigDecimal, rate not null</li>
        </ul>
      </p>

      <h4>Persistable model Cart</h4>
      <p>
        <ul>
          <li>buyer - OnlineBuyer, PK</li>
          <li>curr - Currency, not null, that buyer opted.</li>
          <li>tot - BigDecimal, not null, total</li>
          <li>subt - BigDecimal, not null</li>
          <li>totTx - BigDecimal, not null, total taxes</li>
          <li>items - List&lt;CartLn&gt;</li>
          <li>taxes - List&lt;CartTxLn&gt;</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <h4></h4>
      <p>Persistable model CartTot holds cart totals grouped by seller:
        <ul>
          <li>AHasIdLongVersion (autogenerated ID) fields</li>
          <li>itsOwner - Cart, not null.</li>
          <li>disab - Boolean, do not show in cart, it's for performance</li>
          <li>seller - SeSeller, which items present in cart, NULL means web-store owner's items</li>
          <li>tot - BigDecimal, not null, total</li>
          <li>subt - BigDecimal, not null</li>
          <li>totTx - BigDecimal, not null, total taxes</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model CartLn:
        <ul>
          <li>AHasNameIdLongVersion (autogenerated ID) fields</li>
          <li>itsOwner - Cart, not null.</li>
          <li>disab - Boolean, do not show in cart, it's for performance,
            old purchased cart emptied with this flag, when buyer add new goods to cart then it's used any disabled
            line (if exist) otherwise new line will be created</li>
          <li>seller - SeSeller, which items present in cart, NULL means web-store owner's items</li>
          <li>itTyp - EShopItemType, not null</li>
          <li>itId - Long, not null</li>
          <li>uom - UnitOfMeasure, not null</li>
          <li>price - BigDecimal, not null, grater than zero</li>
          <li>quant - BigDecimal, not null</li>
          <li>subt - BigDecimal, not null</li>
          <li>totTx - BigDecimal, not null</li>
          <li>txDsc - String, Taxes description, uneditable, e.g. "tax1 10%=12, tax2 5%=6"</li>
          <li>tot - BigDecimal, not null</li>
          <li>avQuan - BigDecimal, not null, available quantity to constraint buyer/inform "N items left"</li>
          <li>txCat - tax category, NULL for non-taxable items</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model base ATaxLn:
        <ul>
          <li>AHasIdLongVersion (autogenerated ID) fields</li>
          <li>tax - Tax, not null.</li>
          <li>tot - BigDecimal, not null</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model CartTxLn holds total taxes grouped by invoice:
        <ul>
          <li>ATaxLn fields</li>
          <li>seller - SeSeller, which items presents in cart, NULL means web-store owner's items</li>
          <li>taxab - BigDecimal, not null, taxable amount for invoice basis, 0 - item basis.</li>
          <li>itsOwner - Cart, not null.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model CartItTxLn - cart item's tax line for item basis multi-taxes non-aggregate rate:
        <ul>
          <li>ATaxLn fields</li>
          <li>itsOwner - CartLn, not null.</li>
          <li>disab - Boolean, do not show in cart, it's for performance</li>
          <li>sellerId - SeSeller ID, which items presents in cart, NULL means web-store owner's items.
            It duplicates owner's seller for performance purposes.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Model EShopItemType, enumeration:
        <ul>
          <li>GOODS, goods that stored in shop owner's warehouse, they are usually belongs to the owner.
            Owner can rent his warehouse to store S.E. seller's goods.
            It's org.beigesoft.accounting.persistable.InvItem.</li>
          <li>SERVICE, service that performed by shop owner.
            It's org.beigesoft.accounting.persistable.ServiceToSale.
          </li>
          <li>SEGOODS, goods that located in S.E. seller warehouse.
            It's org.beigesoft.webstore.persistable.SeGoods.
          </li>
          <li>SESERVICE, service that performed by S.E. Seller.
            It's org.beigesoft.webstore.persistable.SeService.
         </li>
        </ul>
      </p>

      <p>Persistable model CustOrder for web-store owner's goods/services:
        <ul>
          <li>AHasNameIdLongVersion (+autogenerated ID) fields</li>
          <li>buyer - OnlineBuyer, not null</li>
          <li>payMeth - EPaymentMethod, not null, ANY default</li>
          <li>place - PickUpPlace, not null.</li>
          <li>curr - Currency, not null, that buyer opted.</li>
          <li>tot - BigDecimal, not null, total</li>
          <li>totTx - BigDecimal, not null, total taxes</li>
          <li>items - List[CustOrderGdLn], ordered goods</li>
          <li>serves - List[CusOrderSrvLn], ordered services</li>
          <li>taxes - List[CustOrderTxLn], taxes</li>
        </ul>
        CustOrderGdLn and CustOrderSrvLn decreased availability of goods/service if GoodsAvailable.isAlways = false.
        It's used to create Sales Invoice.
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model CustOrderTxLn:
        <ul>
          <li>ATaxLn fields</li>
          <li>itsOwner - CustOrder, not null.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model base ACustOrderLn:
        <ul>
          <li>AHasIdLongVersion (autogenerated ID) fields</li>
          <li>itsOwner - CustOrder, not null.</li>
          <li>price - BigDecimal, not null, grater than zero</li>
          <li>quant - BigDecimal, not null, negative means reversing</li>
          <li>subtot - BigDecimal, not null</li>
          <li>totTax - BigDecimal, not null</li>
          <li>taxDescr - String, Taxes description, uneditable, e.g. "tax1 10%=12, tax2 5%=6"</li>
          <li>tot - BigDecimal, not null</li>
          <li>taxCat - InvItemTaxCategory, optional, Origin or destination tax category</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model CustOrderGdLn:
        <ul>
          <li>ACustOrderLn fields</li>
          <li>goods - InvItem, not null.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model CustOrderSrvLn:
        <ul>
          <li>ACustOrderLn fields</li>
          <li>service - ServiceToSale, not null.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model CustOrderSe for S.E.Seller's goods/services:
        <ul>
          <li>AHasNameIdLongVersion (+autogenerated ID) fields</li>
          <li>buyer - OnlineBuyer, not null</li>
          <li>seller - SeSeller, not null.</li>
          <li>payMeth - EPaymentMethod, not null, ANY default</li>
          <li>items - List[CustOrderSeGgLn], ordered S.E.goods</li>
          <li>services - List[CustOrderSeSrvLn], ordered S.E.services</li>
          <li>taxes - List[CustOrderSeTaxLine], taxes</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model CustOrderSeGd:
        <ul>
          <li>ACustOrderLn fields</li>
          <li>goods - SeGoods, not null.</li>
          <li>taxCat - InvItemTaxCategory, optional, Origin or destination tax category</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model CustOrderSeSrvLn:
        <ul>
          <li>ACustOrderLn fields</li>
          <li>service - SeService, not null.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model CustOrderSeTaxLn:
        <ul>
          <li>ATaxLn fields</li>
          <li>itsOwner - CustOrderSe, not null.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Model EPaymentMethod:
        <ul>
          <li>ONLINE, buyer must pay right now with any online method (e.g. credit card, PayPal)</li>
          <li>ANY, it's means that buyer can pay 100% with any method (e.g. with cash when goods has been delivered),
            and if order can be payed partially with several methods,
            e.g. 50% online, 50% bank transfer, cash or cheque.</li>
          <li>CASH, cash.</li>
          <li>BANK_TRANSFER, bank transfer.</li>
          <li>BANK_CHEQUE, bank cheque.</li>
          <li>CASH_BANK_TRANSFER, cash or bank transfer.</li>
          <li>BANK_TRANSFER_CHEQUE, bank transfer or cheque.</li>
          <li>CASH_BANK_TRANSFER_CHEQUE, cash, bank transfer or cheque.</li>
          <li>PARTIAL_ONLINE, in case when order must be payed partially online e.g 50% and the rest
            with any methods - online, bank transfer, cash or cheque.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Persistable model GoodsPaymentMethod to register payment method for a goods:
        <ul>
 p c db f         <li>goods - InvItem, PK</li>
          <li>paymentMethod - EPaymentMethod, not null, ONLINE default.</li>
        </ul>
        TradingSettings.isUsedSeveralPaymentMethods = false by default. It means that web-store uses only payment method,
        and consequently there is no need for dividing customer order. Usually it's online payment.
        For small shop or service maker payment usually is made by cash.
        For S.E.sellers there is no need to truck non-online payments [p]??.
        It will be created orders grouped by payment method and owner for cart items during cart check-out.
        If there is no GoodsPaymentMethod for a goods then it's used TradingSettings.defaultPaymentMethod.
      </p>
      
      <h4>Buyer's(customer's) payments</h4>
      <p>Buyer can pay with several methods: cash, bank money transfer and online methods - credit card, Paypal etc.
        Non-cash-in-hand account (in bank) may be either webstore owner's or S.E. seller's in any way,
        i.e. S.E. seller can receive "payment minus fee" from paid webstore account.
[p]        S.E. Seller can also pay for other services/materials that made by webstore business, e.g. goods storage,
        packaging, delivering, advertising etc., so it's reasonable to create only SalesInvoice for S.E. seller
        that containing all. The best way is let worker to decide -
        "create new invoice or add order fee in existed unaccounted one".
        Online payments entirely handled(by using their checkout page for security reasons) by 3-d party
        - any gateway payment e.g. 2checkout.
        That is means that Beige-Webstore never hold/store customer payments method data like cart number and CVV number(Card Security Code).
      </p>
      
      <h4>Cart checkout</h4>
      <p>The first transaction is goods reservation (create order that decrease available goods if GoodsAvailable.isAlways=false),
[p]        farther is payment transaction.
        In case farther online checkout transaction by 3-d party that is not completed, and buyer
        did not change payment method then reservation (order) is reversed.
        In case of cash or bank transfer order saved with this information. 
      </p>
      
      <h4>Seller payments preferences/requirements</h4>
      <p>Seller webstore or S.E.seller can require desired payment method.
[p]        For example minimum 50% online payments, or 100% cash, or "no credit card" etc.
      </p>
      
      <h4>Customer payments</h4>
      <h5>* Direct payments to S.E. seller with any method (cash, online...)</h5>
      <p>In this case webstore can not control it.
[db][i]        S.E.seller himself mark order as paid. Buyer himself mark order as completed (delivered).
      </p>
      <h5>* Payments to webstore account</h5>
      <p>Customer can change mind about payment method (if this allowed) e.g. pay with cash or online despite
        of chosen "bank transfer method", that is buyer can choose unpaid order and make online payments.
        In case bank transfer buyer can make PaymentNotice for paid order for highlighting this event.
        Buyer should see when payment rich webstore - order should be updated with this information.
      </p>
      <h5>*Partially payments </h5>
      <p><b>Online</b>. Not all online payment gateways allowed partially payments.
        If allowed then customer can make online partially payments himself - he select
        order to pay, enter desired amount (less or equals the rest) and currency and make payments with payment gateway.
      </p>
      
      <h4>Buyer email notification</h4>
      <p>Buyer should receive email of every event:
        <ul>
          <li>Order created</li>
          <li>Order payment (partially or full)</li>
          <li></li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      
      <h4>Customer order changing when customer didn't pick up goods or delivering hasn't started yet ()</h4>
[p]      <p>There are cases:
        <ul>
          <li>Full payments occurred
            <ul>
              <li></li>
            </ul>
          </li>
          <li>Partially paid
          </li>
          <li>Unpaid
          </li>
        </ul>
  In case offline unpaid payment customer can change order during all time till pickup or starting of delivery
        except if it's S.E.seller's goods.
      </p>
    </section>

  </body>

</document>
