<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>Beigesoftware, Beige-WEB-Store</title>
   </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="Beige WEB Store specification. Detail view of goods/services.">

    <h4>Detail view of goods/services.</h4>
    <p>There are cases when goods/services list contains of full information and no more details need.
      If there is goods/service specifics that should not show in the list then this item
      will contains of link to its detail page according Integer ItemInList.detailsMethod and other fields.
      For example item of type SE Seller good and detailsMethod=2 means that will be used concrete JSP page designed for this.
    </p>
    <h5>Customizing view</h5>
    <p>In opposite to the list view detail one should be customized by using JSP code.
      For example JSP will check that SpecificOfItemGroup.description="method1" and render it with this method.
      So SpecificOfItemGroup.teplateStart/End/Detail is useless for detail view cause this is less flexible method.
    </p>
    <h5>Embedded HTML, e.g. SE seller made full description of its goods.</h5>
    <p>It's hard to make reliable view from foreign embedded HTML.
      It must be restricted(current style friendly), embedded HTML editor and the HTML content can be stored in a file (in case of big content).
      This HTML content can uses/contains user downloaded images.
    </p>
    <p>
      The easiest and reliable way is using HTML template in which SE Seller will edit <b>container</b> (part of template) that holds content.
      Then SE Seller will upload this HTML file as item specifics "File embedded". This template (bundle of files) already has all bootstrap CSS files.
      During setting item specifics content in "container" will be verified for using non-accepted HTML tags...
    </p>
    <p>Using embedded HTML (file) describing item is performance friendly method, because SQL server is freed from this and other server (device) may hold these files.</p>
    </section>

  </body>

</document>
